This program that has been created is fiction.
Previously...
[ Episode Three ]
Target aim.
----
What are you doing?
Continue!
Bu.. but...
Target aim!
Fire!
Goo...goo...good shot!
Father.
I wasn't able to say hello to you this morning.
Are you feeling healthy and peaceful?
Healthy and peaceful?
I don't think so.
Since there were extremely horrible things that happened to me last night,
I don't feel healthy and peaceful!
[ Moo Hyul ]
Father...
Please just save me!
Please!
[Taejong: Lee Bang Won]Save you?
I was not myself
last night.
My words and behaviour of last night
was impatient, disobedient, improper,
impolite and ignorant. I am well aware of it.
I also cannot believe
I did such things.
You must be so surprised.
I deserve to die to atone for my sins.
My body,
even the tiny part,
there is nothing
that I did not get from you, Father.
I do not feel wronged when you want me to die.
Just one thing,
dying earlier than my parents is also
undutiful to my parents.
Therefore,
I am just begging you to save my life only.
Father!
Do you really mean it?
Certainly!
I...
will not go against you from now.
Not even a bit.
Regarding all the affairs,
I will follow your command and...
Only...
I will devote myself to learn all from you and
practice it.
Everything?
Yes, I will.
What about the regal authority of armies?
What are you going to do about it?
Regarding commanding the armies,
how dare I can even mimic you?
Do everything as you wish, Father.
If there is anything that is not good enough,
please order me to do it. I will do whatever it is.
You have talked about in the sense of royalty, filial piety and courtesy.
However,
one thing is missing.
Yes, Father!
Please let me know.
Please stand up.
Among what you said,
the only missing thing is
sincerity.
You are a punk without an ounce of sincerity.
Am I wrong?
Since Father is still healthy
and did not lose your insight yet,
I ..
am very happy to see it.
How dare?
Are you being sarcastic towards me?
I am the King of Joseon
that you insist you established.
Please watch your manners.
Didn't you receive an empty food box?
Don't you know its meaning?
I haven't received any food box.
What?
I only received the case resembling magic box puzzle.
All the chambers were empty.
Father...
gave me the solution
that allowed me to solve any box puzzles.
Gathering the strength of only one,
that's me...
Lee Bang Won.
The number one of the box puzzle
represents you, Father.
However, the box puzzle you sent to me this time
was all empty including the middle number.
Therefore, I realized the meaning.
That is...
Joseon where you, Father, does not exist.
I will
live longer than you, Father.
"Prepare for the world when you are absent."
It had that meaning.
The reason that I sent you the empty food box is..
Frankly, I do not really care about its actual meaning.
Whatever your intention was,
it was my own interpretation.
Understanding that way is
better for you, Father.
Because...
other than me..
you have
no alternative plan.
You punk...
must have found your own solutions and answers.
Your Joseon!
Yes.
Now, I
can solve any box puzzles in my own way.
For everything,
if you follow my command,
what are you going to do on your own?
I...
with wise young scholars,
build a small institute,
studying books,
while supporting you, Father.
A palace?
Are you building a palace to study only?
Yes.
If you allow it.
Your answer means
just like that?
At best?
What my plan is like,
you
have yet to know.
Yes,
go ahead.
Build a palace.
As for the name of the palace,
I will also follow your command.
If you give me a name for it. I will take it.
Are you going to gather wise people?
Then,
during the dynasty prior, Goryeo
as well,
I know there was something similar.
Though it was in name only.
Yes.
What is its name?
Just...
Call it Jip-Hyun (wise people's gathering).
Jip-Hyun...
I will do it.
Jip-Hyun.
Jip-Hyun
Jeon (Hall of Wise People)
JIp-Hyun Jeon...
What can you do with it?
Is this
the answer for Joseon that is different from mine?
Jip-Hyun Jeon is the answer?
That's right.
What kind of Joseon is it?
I will close my eyes to power,
and persuade not with the sword but with words.
Gaining people's hearts and accepting them,
instead of leaving only number one in the box puzzle.
2, 3, 4, 5, and 6...
Everyone will find their place and do their bidding.
It will be that sort of Joseon.
Although it will take long, I will be patient and wait.
Waiting?
Waiting...
I...
I will govern the country using only knowledge and learning.
As for the force of army,
I will utilize it only to protect the country from invasion.
Hard shell of the force of army,
and the soft content of knowledge and learning
that is my Joseon.
The rule of right and the rule of might.
It is always a two-bladed sword.
My approach will be different.
Pursuading others through discussion and arguments.
Without making conclusions and being patient
and waiting...
Can't be...
Kyeongyeon (discussion with King) you're referring to.
Precisely so.
You say so because you do not know the aims to which Kyeongyeons were created under?
Yes...
They were established by the founding noblemen to contain King's power.
That's right.
To make a King a puppet,
with the excuse of that pretense to enlighten the King, is such that of Kyeongyeon.
However, you say you will put your sword down and do solely that?
Yes...
That is the beginning of Joseon reformation from Goryeo.
Joseon's politic and ideal of Neo-Confucianism.
Was Joseon established 100 or 200 year ago?
It has been 26 years.
Right.
It has been only 26 years.
If Joseon
will be sustained 50 years or 500 years.
No one knows yet.
Since no one dies with hunger in the city,
do you think it is a peaceful reign or something?
But...
wait and pursuade people?
be patient?
But...
you are going to waste time on some discussion?
No it is not!
It is wasting!
You have to establish the foundations of the country and gather the will power.
And unite the strengths as one.
That is what the King of a 26-year-old nation has to do.
The position of a king of Joseon
is not that kind of relaxing position.
No.
Mil-bon [ hidden root ].
Have you ever heard of Mil-bon?
Yes...
Isn't that the rumor among the street gossipers?
There is a secret society of traitors called Mil-bon.
That is not just a rumour.
Father.
Do you possibly believe it?
Jeong Do Jeon, that man made Mil-Bon.
How should you believe in such idle talk of the town?
Jeong Do-Jeon's party are mostly killed or exiled. The survivors all lost their power.
Who can lead that kind of corps?
Isn't Jeong Gi-Joon still alive?
Year of Gichook (1409).
The protagonist of the Chodongyoseo.
Jeong Do-Jeon's nephew,
Jeong Gi Joon.
Aren't you thinking of this because of him?
Because of the incident that happened in year of Gi-Chook (the year of the Earth Ox - 1409),
that is why you aim to carry out Kyeongyeon or whatever it is, isn't it?
Aren't you saying all these?
Is it not right?
I...
don't remember who he was.
Is he a relative of Jeong Do-Jeon?
[ won (u5143) ]
[ Do-Dahm Daek ]
Master, Bon-Won
finally,
I got Mil-Bon's book in my hand.
Boss.
I am coming in.
Oh, right. Come in.
How is he?  I haven't seen anyone like him.
He bawls and squalls.
He is extremely stubborn at the age of only 12 years old or so.
I think we should starve him for a few days.
Watch him well.
Yes.
Jeong...Gi...Joon.
Is it really because of him?
You...can't do anything.
Jeong...Gi...Joon.
[ 9 years ago ]
Joseon's founding of more than a decade following the teachings of Zhuxi.
[ Prince Choong Nyung, Lee Do: future King Sejong ]
----
Largely...
the fact that Joseon's system is based on the old kingdom of Jooh (u5468).
all the scholars are aware of it.
Also...
the standing king is only a false king.
The true king is the bodies of government in whole. Such is a truth known to all.
This is...
the basic principles of Sam Bong who established Joseon.
[ Jeong Gi-Joon ]
Not everyone is permitted to come in here.
Only people who follow the teachings of Confucious and Mencius...
are permitted to come in here.
You are not supposed to come in here.
How dare you?
Seeing your clothing, you must be a prince.
You are the son of the King.
You brat!
Not only your writing, but also your behaviour is so impolite.
Who are you?
I said... what?
Jeong Gi-Joon!
Who is this guy?
The younger brother of Jeong Do-Jeon,
he is Jeong Do-Kwang's son.
Capture him... now!
Impolite?
To become a leader,
the great treasure of an adult is authority and the great virtue on earth is life.
How should one guard such authority?
I will tell you, it is benevolence.
The talented offer wisdom.
The heroic offer strength.
Divide among the people and each carrying out their role,
solely and exclusively.
following the command of the King.
What are you talking about?
I am..
I am a prince of Joseon.
Do you think I am not aware of the laws of Joseon?
And are you citing it for me?
Then...
cite the text.
The people below..
The people below look powerless
but they cannot be threatened by power.
Although they look unwise,
they cannot be decieved with wisdom.
The king is...
the person who does that?
Is he the person who does not threaten people with power?
Ah... instead of threatening, he gives death.
His younger brother,
his brother and collegues.
You seriously!
Oh, all right.
He could do that as he is also a human.
Therefore, Sam Bong (Jeong Do-Jeon) established Kyeongyeon
to teach the king about Confucianism.
Also Sah-Gwan to restrict the king.
The six ministries and a leader to oversee as the head of the government.
He also made prime minister.
To make a virtuous king.
However,
the king holds Kyeongyeon
only a couple times per year?!
Intimidating the ministers.
This time, he made the prime minister a puppet.
He controls the 6 departments on his own.
However...
the reason I showed up at the examination is not that.
Your father
killed my uncle.
It is not because he demolished everything that my uncle established!
If he demolished it,
it is right to withdraw the justice and writing that my uncle placed initially.
To tempt the scholars and noblemen who established Joseon,
being afraid of their leaving,
he must not fake those principles!
That is the manner!
That is...
the MANNER of the person who persues Confucianism at least a little bit!
Your Father..
stole Joseon from Sam-Bong.
He is a thief...
and a murderer!
There is nothing different from your father.
Only using violence.
Hurry up!
Quickly!
[ Jeong Do-Kwang, younger brother of Jeong Do-Jeon ]
Mencius said the people are the most precious. The king who protects...
Master! The fat is in the fire!
What's wrong?
Master, you have to run away!
You guys should run away too!
I asked you what happened!
Young master Gi-Joon went to take a royal exam.
What?
Regardless.
The army has almost arrived here.
Now, hurry.
Spare me, Sir.
Did Jeong Do-Kwang teach children in this town?
Yes, he did but...
Where is he?
Well, I don't know.
See?
Even a criticism from a young scholar,
your father pays it back as death.
That is the king of this country.
No.
Can't be.
He will not kill the people with that reason.
It must be a misunderstanding.
Misunderstanding?
I will not ask twice.
Jeong Do-Kwang, and his son, Jeong Gi-Joon,
where are they?
I really don't know.
I will solve this problem.
Seeing you are holding me,
now you seem to know what your father is doing.
Also, you know that
you can't save anyone and
you can't do anything.
It's me!
I am Jeong Gi-Joon!
Get up.
Let me go!
I will go on my own!
Chase them! Chase them!
You cannot do anything!
Thats right, Jeong Gi-Joon.
Jeong Gi-Joon.
Jeong Gi-Joon
Jeong Gi-Joon...
Jeong Do-Kwang...
How did it go?
I'm sorry.
I lost him.
Take away all the pots.
Huh?
A place like this in the house...
Your Majesty!
Here!
Read it!
Yes.
If a king is a flower,
its root is a minister.
When its flower is not healthy,
the tree is not going to die but
when the root is not healthy, the tree will die.
The unhealthy flower...
What are you doing? Read it!
can be just broken off.
Your Majesty!
This guy must be crazy!
Why don't you return, now?
Keep reading.
It's not worth reading!
Didn't I order you to read?
Your Majesty!
Get away!
The king only
decides the minister
and it is the position where he discusses things with the minister.
It is just the luxurious symbolic figure of Joseon.
The root of Joseon is the minister.
Your Majesty!
The noblemen of Joseon,
become the root!
Be the scholars sustaining Joseon,
train the great officials and select the wise and able minister!
As a result, the tree of Joseon can last for thousands of years.
Be the root of the roots!
This is what I, Jeong Do-Jeon...
This is what I, Jeong Do-Jeon
am the root of the roots!
The hidden root.
Mil-Bon!
Why I made Mil-Bon.
you, noblemen,
be the roots of Joseon!
Become the Mil-Bon!
Protect Joseon!
Mil-Bon's first member, Jeong Do-Jeon.
Your Majesty!
He is already a dead man!
It is just the void daydreaming of a person who was once avid for the power.
Your Majesty!
This was it!
This was it...
What are you talking now, Your Majesty?
The thing he told me when he was dying.
Its meaning...
The flower is just the flower.
It cannot become the root or
get rid of the root.
You can't...
It is Mil-Bon...
Jeong Do-Jeon,
He made the secret corps.
Isn't it the sound of an owl?
Is Jo Mal-Saeng out there?
Why are you coming in?
Your Majesty.
[ Park Eun ]
Jo Mal-Saeng seems to have traced Jeong Gi-Joon and his father's movement.
Is that right?
Your Majesty!
Jo Mal-Saeng has been doing something suspicious.
Suspicious behaviour?
Without the royal command, was he moving the army of the Royal Investigation Bureau?
Yes!
However, Your Majesty!
[ Lee Shin Jeok ]
How were you aware of this already?
Jo Mal Saeng is moving under Grand King Former's secret command.
Secret command?
He's been looking for Jeong Gi-Joon and his father covertly.
Yes?
Find out where Jo Mal Saeng moved the army along.
Let me know, right away!
Your Majesty, how come?
What are you doing?
There is no time to lose. No time.
Yes, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty,
what on earth are you trying to do?
Now, Moo Hyul it is your turn.
Is it true for sure?
Yes, Your Highness.
We received communication from those we've dispatched here and there.
It must be reliable.
Accordingly, did Jo Mal Saeng do something?
Yes, Your Highness.
Subtitles brought to you by Deep Rooted Friends @ viki.com
Over there! Chase after them!
From north to south village and high to low, we searched everywhere.
But we did not find them.
Not there?
If they ran away riding horses, the sound must have been heard.
It is not possible they are not there.
Then...
They must have gotten off the horse and hidden somewhere.
North, South, High, Low.
If they were nowhere there,
then only one place is left!
It is Ban-Chon!
Do you mean Ban-Chon?
Ban-Chon?
Did they sneak into Ban-Chon?
Yes!
Therefore, the army is surrounding the Ban-Chon but
we cannot get in there without the Royal command.
I was told to come and receive the royal command at once.
But...
there are the shrines of Confucious and Moon Sun Gong.
We cannot allow the army to intrude there.
Isn't it just some custom made by the nobles?
Your Majesty...
Protecting Jeong Gi-Joon,
itself means the conflict with the former king.
A conflict...
Your Majesty!
That's right. It is a conflict...
He should not be alive in my father's Joseon.
In my Joseon,
and in my Jip-Hyun Jeon,
I need him, Jeong Gi-Joon.
Therefore, as long as you hear from them,
go right away,
bring Jeong Gi-Joon to me.
Capture and bring him to me!
However Your Majesty!
If the fact that the Royal army's intrusion to Ban-Chon was revealed,
the Confucian scholars won't just sit and watch.
We must capture him!
However, if the reason is due to him being the younger brother of Jeong Do Jeon,
those scholar's concern about Jeong Do-Jeon and his family...
You know very well about it.
I know! Since I know it,
Jeong Do Gwang.
Jeong Gi-Joon has to be
murdered secretly.
Jeong Do Gwang, perhaps not.
Jeong Gi-Joon will be a big trouble.
By fair means or foul, certainly this time,
you should capture those Jeongs.
But...
You should forward it to Jo Mal Saeng.
However, I did not allow him to intrude into Ban-Chon.
Yes, I understand that.
Minister...
Bring a group of soldiers
wait at the outside of Ban-Chon!
Yes,
I will do as you ordered.
----
Orabeoni (in dialect).
You've come.
You must be tired.
Shall we rest for awhile.
Shit.
AAAH shit. Crap.
This is exhausting.
Have you come?
No suspicious movements?
No.
What's wrong?
Did anything happen?
The king's men are under tight search.
When we went to drop off the message, we nearly suffered attack.
We were able to shake them off, but it's a worry.
Howevever, it is the shrine of Moon Sun Gong,
isn't it the safest place in Joseon?
It is true.. but
Lee Bang Won will not care about those things.
Even so, without abandoning the Confucian scholars, he can't invade here.
Don't worry about it.
Until when do we have to do the rituals this way?
I must pay back these grudges, Hyung Nim (older brother).
That day doesn't seem too far away.
Finally, I found it.
What did you find?
Well..
Did you possibly?
Yes.
Hyung-Nim!
Hyung Nim!
Hyung Nim, finally we found the Mil-Bon letter.
The letter hand written by you, we finally found it.
It's done.
Since we didn't have this Mil-Bon letter until now,
it was quite difficult to reestablish Mil-Bon.
However, now my brother is behind me.
I can establish Mil-Bon again!
Yes!
Now, you can become the 2nd chief of Mil-Bon.
Teacher Sam-Bong is with you!
All Confucian scholars will follow you.
Did His Highness Grand King Former, really command that way?
Yes!
I got it!
How did it go?
They seemed to sneak into Moon Sung Gong's shrine.
That shrine?
Intrude into Moon Sung Gong's shrine.
Also, from now on, we are not the Royal army.
Do you get it?
Yes!
You have to act as fast and secretly as possible.
If anyone of you get caught, the prosecutor's department will deny any relations.
We will not be responsible for anything for you. You will die as a traitor.
You must succeed as fast and secretly as possible without any dropout!
Do you understand?
Yes!
Take off your uniforms and wear black clothing with a mask on.
Your Majesty, Dongbu Dae-eon (Royal Messenger) is coming in.
Where are they?
They are in Ban-Chon.
Ban-Chon?
Yes...
Did possibly my father allow the army to intrude into Ban-Chon?
I do not know if he allowed it in person.
Jo Mal Saeng's men are around Ban-Chon.
Lord Park Eun also is heading toward the outside of Ban-Chon.
We are already late.
Now, all we have is you.
Go ahead. Now!
Your Majesty! Are you sure?
You have to save Jeong Do-Gwang and Jeong Gi-Joon!
Unquestioningly, you must bring them alive!
Do you get it?
I will follow your command!
Where?
Aww, why can't I reach it?
Where is it?
A bit...a bit more...
Ohh, I made it!
Subtitles brought to you by Deep Rooted Friends Team at viki.com
Damn it!
We can't.
I mean,
why doesn't your mother like me?
I have no idea.
Persuade my mother.
What punk wheedles?
Hey, let's have a baby first!
Don't do that.
Don't do this!  Stay calm!
Stay still.
What is that?
Help me!
Please help me!
Save me!
What's with all the noise.
Catch the brat!
Catch him!
Hurry and catch him.
Hey, this way!
Jang Seung forest...
Isnt' the crazy boy going into the shrine?
Block him!
How are Gi-Joon and Pyung doing?
Yes, they stay secretly at a place where no one knows about.
Just a kid.
Not just one punk.
Why you little cow.
It seems that they are on the same side.
Who are you?
Get away from here.
Assasins are here.
This way.
If you go this way, it connects to Jang Seung forest.
Master!
I asked you who the heck you are?
What is this commotion?
Who are you, you guys?
Don't you know where this is?
This place is the shrine
for Moon Sung Gong who introduced Confucianism to this land!
Even the Royal army cannot come in here because of this place.
How dare you slash swords here?
Who the heck are you?
Attack!
Beat them up!
Ggeut Soo!
Elder.
Hurry, hurry up!
You brat!
Master!
This way!
To the north of Ban-Chon, two horses are leaving rapidly.
Move out at once.
Let's go.
Take charge of this place!
I will chase after Jeong Do Gwang.
Wait in ambush over there.
Yes, Sir.
To the left, into the mountain.
Stop there! Stop!
What's wrong?
Mil-Bon letter!
The horse that he rode away carries the Mil-Bon letter!
Oh the pouch!
Father's last will.
The pouch!
I have been looking for the past 20 years.
I can't leave without it!
I will look for it!
Master, please get away from this area!
Master! Master!
We have to find it! Mil-Bon letter!
First, you have to get away from here.
Stop! I have to find it!
My father's last will.
I have to return! Stop! Stop!
Please, stop!
Go back, go back.
I told you to go back. Hey!
Go back!
Please, go back!
Ah damn it!
Troops from the Royal Investigation Bureau are dispatched on both sides of the forest.
At least 100 heads of army on east and north.
It's this way.
What is that sound?
Over there, Lord Jo Mal Saeng is chasing someone.
I got it.
Let's go!
We have to find
the Mil-Bon letter.
You must capture them!
I have to find
my father's last will.
Surely,
save them!